少し休みますか
Should we rest a while?
She was still the princess I'd always known.
昔から見てきた
The princess who'd never experienced filth or pain.
汚れや痛みなどを知らない姫だった
Boy...
小僧目
Three Years Ago
I told you to attend today's clan meeting.
今日の五族会議 お前も出席しろって言ったろうが
会議ならムンドク様のみ出席なさればよかろう
You're the only one who needs to attend the meeting, Lord Mun-deok.
Besides, I can't be bothered to listen to King Il's happy-go-lucky nonsen-
それに ぽよんとしたイル陛下の話には付き合っ...
Fool!
バカ者
Don't call me "Lord Mun-deok"! Call me "Grandpa"!
ムンドク様ではない 爺ちゃんと呼べ
That's why you're upset?
そっちかよ
俺とあんたは血繋がってねぇだろが
We aren't even related by blood!
血がどうした そんなもん愛の前には無力
Blood? In the face of love, blood is powerless!
Now, now...
こら こら
If the two of you start fighting,
you might wreck the castle.
ムンドク将軍とハクが暴れたら
緋龍城が吹き飛んじゃうじゃないか
I apologize, King Il.
これはイル陛下
It's all right.
いいの いいの
Uh-oh. I called him "happy-go-lucky."
やべぇ ぽよんとか言っちまった
It's been a while, Hak.
久しぶりだね ハク
It's been lonely since you stopped coming to play.
昔見たい遊びに来てくれなくて寂しいよ
Well, a commoner like me can't just walk into the castle freely.
いや 俺みたいな平民が気軽には
Don't worry about that.
そんなの気にしないで
Yona's also been lonely without you.
ヨナもハクが居ないと寂しがっている
You happy-go-lucky liar.
嘘つけ このぽよん
Happy-go-lucky?
ぽよん？
But it's the perfect phrase!
ぽよんと何じゃあ
What's that supposed to mean?
But it's the perfect phrase!
Violence is never the answer, Mun-deok.
暴力はいけないよ ムンドク
Hak's honesty is what I love about him.
私はハクの裏表のない所がお気に入りなんだ
Have a steamed bun.
お饅頭あげるね
So, Hak, would you stay at the castle permanently, as Yona's bodyguard?
だからハク ヨナの護衛として
ずっと城にいてくれないかい
陛下
Your Majesty,
I find nobility a terrible bother.
俺は貴族ってのが面倒で仕方ないんですよ
If I serve at the castle or become a general,
城に入ったり将軍になったりすれば
I won't be able to take long naps at home.
家でのんびり昼寝もできない
Hak...
ハク
You hate weapons, don't you?
陛下は武器はお嫌いなのでしょう
Then see if you can find a precious rarity like this one:
なら武器も持たずに人を護衛する
世にも貴重な人間を探して下さいよ
a guard who can protect without a weapon.
Hak...
ハク
Episode 3:   The Distant Sky
正直 王家や貴族とは関わりたくない
Frankly, I don't want anything to do with nobility or the royal family.
腹の探り合いも足の引っ張り合いもくだらねぇ
The way they probe each other's intentions and drag each other down is ridiculous.
王は王で危機感ねぇしな
The king has no sense of danger, either.
And the other reason I don't want to come to this castle permanently is...
そして この城来たくないもう一つの理由は
Hak!
ハク
Hide me.
隠して
When I'm around the princess...
この姫さんと居ると 俺は調子狂って仕方ない
I'm overcome by this weird feeling.
Princess Yona!
ヨナ姫 どこです
Where are you?
Princess Yona!
ヨナ姫
ダメですよ ヨナ姫
That's no good, Princess Yona.
You have to make sure people
don't find out it was you.
いたずらはばれない様にしないと
That's not what I was doing.
違うわよ
Huh? He's courting you?
言い寄られてる
本当だってば
It's true!
A man called Kang Tae-jun
あのカンテジュンとか言う人
keeps visiting the castle to give me gifts and inviting me to play with him.
度々城に来ては私に贈り物やら遊びに誘ったりするのよ
Princess, let's play!
姫 遊びましょう
The son of the Fire Tribe chief, huh?
火の部族のご子息がね
He's awfully persistent.
凄くしつこいのよ
Then why not tell him you have
your heart set on Su-won?
言ってやれば良いではないですか
私にはスウォンと言う心に決めた人が居ますって
But my feelings aren't returned.
だって 片思いだし
If I said that, Su-won would hear about it.
それを言ったらスウォン本人の耳にも入っちゃう
That's not my problem.
俺の知った事じゃねぇ
Don't make it sound like such a bother.
面倒臭そうに言わないで
This is why I hate coming to the castle.
だから城に来るのは嫌なんだ
Then you'll have to find a way to get along with Lord Kang Tae-jun.
じゃ カンテジュン様と適当に仲良くするんですね
You're so cold, Hak.
ハク 冷たい
Su-won would never say that.
スウォンなら絶対そんな事言わないわ
だったらスウォン様に守ってくれと泣きつきゃいいだろうが
In that case, go cry to Lord Su-won and ask him to protect you!
Let's hurry back to the clan mansion, General Mun-deok.
早く部族の屋敷へ戻ろうぜ ムンドク将軍
What are you so irritated about?
何を苛ついとるんだ
そして爺ちゃんと呼べ
Also, call me "Grandpa."
I'm not irritated.
苛ついて何かいませんよ
苛ついとるんだな
You are irritated.
Princess Yona...
ヨナ姫
What are you doing here?
何でここに
There...
I'm sorry about this afternoon.
昼間はごめんなさい
You got angry because I was acting weak, right?
私が不甲斐ないから怒ったんでしょう
I'm the proud princess of the Kingdom of Kouka.
私は高華国の誇りある姫なんだから
Instead of complaining, I'll do
something about it myself.
ウダウダ言ってないで 自分で何とかしてみる
じゃね
Bye.
H-Hey...
You can have those.
それ あげる
I'm bribing you to reconcile with me.
仲直りの賄賂ね
This is why I want nothing to do with the princess.
だから 姫さんとは関わりたくねんだよ
At this rate, the clans will gain power, and the king's power will wane.
このままでは部族達の力が増し
国王の力が劣れる一方だ
Should we really leave such a cowardly king in charge of this country?
あの様な臆病な王にこの国を任せて良いのか
They're really letting him have it.
言われてる 言われてる
Considering the kind of king he is, it's no wonder.
無理もないか あの王じゃなぁ
Happy-go-lucky
But he's a nice guy.
If I succeed Grandpa and become a general, I'll be the royal family's dog.
俺が爺ちゃんの後を継いで将軍になったら
俺は王家の犬...か
Hak, would you stay at the castle permanently, as Yona's bodyguard?
ハク ヨナの護衛としてずっと城に居てくれないかい
You don't want to do that, Your Majesty. I'm...
止めといた方がいいですよ陛下 俺は...
嫌です
No!
I won't go to the royal villa with you.
私はあなたとは離宮には行きません
Don't be so cold.
つれない事を仰らずに
Won't you show me the way?
案内しては下さらぬか
Let go!
放して
They're so annoying.
うぜぇ
If only Su-won were around...
スウォンが居ればなぁ
Someone should stop him!
誰かお止めしろ
しかしカン将軍の子息だぞ
But that's General Kang's son.
下手な事したら...
One wrong move, and...
Then go get the king.
では 陛下をお呼びしろ
Nobles really are bothersome creatures.
貴族様とは誠に面倒な生き物だ
Don't get involved. Leave them be.
関わるな ほって置け
Otherwise, for the rest of my life, I'll...
でないと俺は これからずっと...
放して
Let go!
もう 放してのよ
Let go of me!
You really are adorable.
本当に可愛いらしいですね
まるで子猫の様な力で抗われるとは
益々触れたくなって仕舞いますよ
When you struggle with a kitten's strength, it makes me want to touch you more.
That's enough.
いい加減に...
That's enough, Lord Kang Tae-jun.
いい加減になさいませ カンテジュン殿
Ouch!
いたたたた
Hak...
ハク
H-How rude!
無礼者
How dare you casually touch the princess?!
姫に気安く触れるなど
And who gave you permission to touch my princess?
あなたこそ 誰の許可を得て
俺の姫に触れやがってるんですか
My?
"My"?
俺の？
Whose?
誰の？
Y-You should watch your mouth, brat!
ガ ガキが出任せを
I'm not lying.
嘘ではありませんって
俺と姫は幼少時より将来を誓い合った仲ですよ
When the princess and I were children,
we pledged to spend our futures together.
Right, Princess?
ね 姫様
Huh?
Princess, there's no need to be shy.
姫様 そんなに照れなくても
Ha, ha... Not in front of other people!
ほ ほ ほ 嫌ね 人前で
Princess, do you love him?
姫はそう奴がお好きなのですか
Y-Yeah.
I love him.
好き 大好き
I really love him.
I-I refuse to accept this!
み...認めん
Why would a princess pledge her future to someone like you?!
貴様の様な者が姫と将来を誓うなど
I am Kang Tae-jun, the second son of the Fire Tribe's General Kang!
私は火の部族長のカン将軍が次男
カンテジュンなるぞ
And who, exactly, are you?
貴様はどこの誰だと言うんだ
I'm the Wind Tribe's next general, Son Hak.
俺は風の部族次期将軍 ソンハク
The king himself appointed me to be Princess Yona's bodyguard.
陛下直々に ヨナ姫様専属護衛を命ぜられた者
異存あるか
Any objections?
Then show me your true strength-
ならばその実力 見せてみよ
Your Majesty!
陛下
Don't do that.
いけませんよ
Please forgive me.
お許しを
It's all right.
いいの いいの
I had no idea you felt that way about each other.
君達がそう言う仲だとは知らなかったよ
F-Father, this is a misunderstanding!
ち 父上誤解よ
But after what we said,
I doubt he'll be back.
まぁああ言えば もう彼も来ないでしょう
Hak, you've finally come around to the idea of being Yona's bodyguard.
ハク やっとヨナの護衛をする気になったんだね
I knew I could count on you.
君になら任せられると思っていた
I don't come cheap.
高いですよ 俺は
Please. Look after Yona.
どうか ヨナを頼む
As you wish.
御意
Jeez.
まったく
もう本当しつこいのよ 嫌なんだ
He's terribly persistent. I just can't stand it.
I can't leave this father and daughter alone.
この親子はどうも放っておけねぇ
It's all right.
それにこの王は臆病などではない
Besides, this king is no coward.
And he won't listen to me at all.
King Il, are you still watching over us somewhere?
イル陛下 今もどこかで俺らを見ておいでか
I'll protect your daughter in your stead!
貴方の心残りは俺が守る
Don't cry, Father.
泣かないで父上
Even if Mother is gone, I'm still here.
母上が居なくなても ヨナが居るから
You're not alone, Father.
父上は一人じゃないよ
そしてね ヨナにはスウォンがついてるから
And I have Su-won.
Yona!
ヨナ
Look, it's snow!
ほら見て 雪ですよ
Yeah.
I made a dumpling.
お団子出来ました
何だか奇怪な物が出来ました
I made a strange creature.
Yona...
ヨナ
I-I'm doing great!
元気だよ
I have to be cheerful, so my father won't cry!
父上が泣かないようにヨナが元気になるんだもんね
Huh?
You're heavy.
重い
Hak!
ハク
わい ハクだ
Hooray, it's Hak!
Princess, watch your step.
姫さん 足元に気付けろよ
I was in a good mood too.
せっかくいい気分だったのに
Why are you lying down there?
何でそんな所で寝てるのよ
I was engraving proof of my existence on the Earth.
俺の生きた証をこの大地に刻でたんだよ
Huh?
When the ground is white with snow,
降り積もった白い雪があったら
it's human nature to lie down in it.
まず大の字になって寝てみたくなるのが人情ってもんだぜ
白 帥爆
Hak's so cool
You're the perfect target for snow dumplings.
雪団子の的にちょうどいいわ
Really?
さすがハク ヨナが元気になりました
Well done, Hak! Yona is full of energy again!
Yona's energy has disappeared.
ヨナの元気がなくなりました
I guess playing in the snow was a bit too much for the princess.
雪ん中での遊びは 姫さんにはきつかったか
I'm sorry, Yona.
ごめんね ヨナ
If you rest and take your medicine, you'll get better.
お薬を飲んで安静になされたら よくなりますよ
Where is Father?
ね 父上は
His Majesty is busy right now.
陛下は今お忙しくて
But he'll come to see you soon.
ですが直にお見えになりますよ
It's okay, Yona.
大丈夫ですよ ヨナ
When he hears that you're sick,
the king will come running.
あの王様 姫さんが病気つったら飛んでくるぞ
You two can leave now.
二人共もう帰っていいよ
If you get close to me...
ヨナに近づいたら...
We're fine. We feel great.
平気ですよ 元気ですから
Our bodies are really warm!
今体ポカポカで
俺何か遊び過ぎてまだ雪団子の幻が見える
I played so hard that I can still see snow dumplings.
Doctor, you have more patients!
医務官 病人出た
No wonder I saw snow dumplings flying around me.
道理で雪団子が俺の回りを飛んでると思った
Don't you two need to leave?
二人共 帰らなくていいの
Apparently it's best for us to recover here,
so we don't spread our illness.
病を流行らせない様に
ここで治した方がいいらしいです
But because I've been holding your hand when you sleep, nothing has changed.
でもヨナとは最近ずっと手を繋いで寝てるし
いつも通りですね
You've been doing that?
そんな事してんの お前ら
I'm leaving.
やっぱ俺帰るわ
Huh? Let's all hold hands.
三人で手を繋ぎましょうよ
You can't be-
冗談
爺ちゃん
Grandpa!
ROAR
Boy, I heard you threw snow on the princess and made her sick.
小僧 姫様に雪をぶつけて病にかけたらしいが
ROAR
When there's snow lying around,
it's only right to throw it!
そこに雪があったら投げるのが礼儀だろ
尻を出せ
Show me your rear!
I'll give you a whipping!
鞭打ちじゃ
General, that's enough!
将軍 お止め下さい
They're sick.
病人ですよ
Grandpa gets in
trouble and leaves.
m 807 79 l 1142 79 1142 211 807 211
Grandpa gets in
trouble and leaves.
m 807 79 l 1142 79 1142 211 807 211
Grandpa gets in
trouble and leaves.
m 807 79 l 1142 79 1142 211 807 211
Grandpa gets in
trouble and leaves.
m 807 79 l 1142 79 1142 211 807 211
Grandpa gets in
trouble and leaves.
m 807 79 l 1142 79 1142 211 807 211
Grandpa gets in
trouble and leaves.
m 807 79 l 1142 79 1142 211 807 211
Grandpa gets in
trouble and leaves.
m 807 79 l 1142 79 1142 211 807 211
Grandpa gets in
trouble and leaves.
m 807 79 l 1142 79 1142 211 807 211
Grandpa gets in
trouble and leaves.
m 807 79 l 1142 79 1142 211 807 211
Grandpa gets in
trouble and leaves.
m 807 79 l 1142 79 1142 211 807 211
Grandpa gets in
trouble and leaves.
m 807 79 l 1142 79 1142 211 807 211
Grandpa gets in
trouble and leaves.
m 807 79 l 1142 79 1142 211 807 211
Grandpa gets in
trouble and leaves.
m 807 79 l 1142 79 1142 211 807 211
Grandpa gets in
trouble and leaves.
m 807 79 l 1142 79 1142 211 807 211
Grandpa gets in
trouble and leaves.
m 807 79 l 1142 79 1142 211 807 211
Grandpa gets in
trouble and leaves.
m 807 79 l 1142 79 1142 211 807 211
Grandpa gets in
trouble and leaves.
m 807 79 l 1142 79 1142 211 807 211
Grandpa gets in
trouble and leaves.
m 807 79 l 1142 79 1142 211 807 211
Grandpa gets in
trouble and leaves.
m 807 79 l 1142 79 1142 211 807 211
Grandpa gets in
trouble and leaves.
m 807 79 l 1142 79 1142 211 807 211
Grandpa gets in
trouble and leaves.
m 807 79 l 1142 79 1142 211 807 211
I'll stay here, after all.
Grandpa gets in
trouble and leaves.
m 807 79 l 1142 79 1142 211 807 211
Grandpa gets in
trouble and leaves.
m 807 79 l 1142 79 1142 211 807 211
Grandpa gets in
trouble and leaves.
m 807 79 l 1142 79 1142 211 807 211
俺 ここに居るわ
Grandpa gets in
trouble and leaves.
m 807 79 l 1142 79 1142 211 807 211
Grandpa gets in
trouble and leaves.
m 807 79 l 1142 79 1142 211 807 211
Grandpa gets in
trouble and leaves.
m 807 79 l 1142 79 1142 211 807 211
Grandpa gets in
trouble and leaves.
m 807 79 l 1142 79 1142 211 807 211
Grandpa gets in
trouble and leaves.
m 807 79 l 1142 79 1142 211 807 211
Grandpa gets in
trouble and leaves.
m 807 79 l 1142 79 1142 211 807 211
Grandpa gets in
trouble and leaves.
m 807 79 l 1142 79 1142 211 807 211
Grandpa gets in
trouble and leaves.
m 807 79 l 1142 79 1142 211 807 211
Grandpa gets in
trouble and leaves.
m 807 79 l 1142 79 1142 211 807 211
Grandpa gets in
trouble and leaves.
m 807 79 l 1142 79 1142 211 807 211
Grandpa gets in
trouble and leaves.
m 807 79 l 1142 79 1142 211 807 211
Grandpa gets in
trouble and leaves.
m 807 79 l 1142 79 1142 211 807 211
Grandpa gets in
trouble and leaves.
m 807 79 l 1142 79 1142 211 807 211
Grandpa gets in
trouble and leaves.
m 807 79 l 1142 79 1142 211 807 211
Grandpa gets in
trouble and leaves.
m 807 79 l 1142 79 1142 211 807 211
Grandpa gets in
trouble and leaves.
m 807 79 l 1142 79 1142 211 807 211
Grandpa gets in
trouble and leaves.
m 807 79 l 1142 79 1142 211 807 211
Grandpa gets in
trouble and leaves.
m 807 79 l 1142 79 1142 211 807 211
Grandpa gets in
trouble and leaves.
m 807 79 l 1142 79 1142 211 807 211
Grandpa gets in
trouble and leaves.
m 807 79 l 1142 79 1142 211 807 211
Grandpa gets in
trouble and leaves.
m 807 79 l 1142 79 1142 211 807 211
Grandpa gets in
trouble and leaves.
m 807 79 l 1142 79 1142 211 807 211
Grandpa gets in
trouble and leaves.
m 807 79 l 1142 79 1142 211 807 211
Grandpa gets in
trouble and leaves.
m 807 79 l 1142 79 1142 211 807 211
Grandpa gets in
trouble and leaves.
m 807 79 l 1142 79 1142 211 807 211
Grandpa gets in
trouble and leaves.
m 807 79 l 1142 79 1142 211 807 211
Grandpa gets in
trouble and leaves.
m 807 79 l 1142 79 1142 211 807 211
Grandpa gets in
trouble and leaves.
m 807 79 l 1142 79 1142 211 807 211
Grandpa gets in
trouble and leaves.
m 807 79 l 1142 79 1142 211 807 211
Grandpa gets in
trouble and leaves.
m 807 79 l 1142 79 1142 211 807 211
Grandpa gets in
trouble and leaves.
m 807 79 l 1142 79 1142 211 807 211
Grandpa gets in
trouble and leaves.
m 807 79 l 1142 79 1142 211 807 211
Grandpa gets in
trouble and leaves.
m 807 79 l 1142 79 1142 211 807 211
Grandpa gets in
trouble and leaves.
m 807 79 l 1142 79 1142 211 807 211
Grandpa gets in
trouble and leaves.
m 807 79 l 1142 79 1142 211 807 211
Grandpa gets in
trouble and leaves.
m 807 79 l 1142 79 1142 211 807 211
Grandpa gets in
trouble and leaves.
m 807 79 l 1142 79 1142 211 807 211
Grandpa gets in
trouble and leaves.
m 807 79 l 1142 79 1142 211 807 211
If I go home, he'll kill me.
帰ったら殺される
m 807 79 l 1142 79 1142 211 807 211
Grandpa gets in
trouble and leaves.
m 807 79 l 1142 79 1142 211 807 211
Grandpa gets in
trouble and leaves.
m 807 79 l 1142 79 1142 211 807 211
Grandpa gets in
trouble and leaves.
本字幕由✿花語&花丸字幕組✿共同製作
m 807 79 l 1142 79 1142 211 807 211
That's the Wind Tribe chief,
General Mun-deok, isn't it?
あれは風の部族長ムンドク将軍ですよね
Yeah.
そうだけど
I admire General Mun-deok.
ムンドク将軍 私の憧れなんです
I had no idea he was your grandfather.
ハクのお爺様だった何て
I'm an orphan.
俺は孤児だ
We aren't blood relatives.
爺ちゃんとは血繋がってないぞ
I see.
そうなんですか
I'm only his adopted son.
養子として世話になってるだけだ
But Mun-deok came to see you.
でもムンドク来てくれた
He must love you.
ハクの事好きなんだね
I don't know.
どうかな
Someone's here again.
また誰か来た
F-Father, what are you doing here?
ち 父上 どうしてここに
Is there something wrong with
a father coming to see his ill son?
病にかかった息子を見舞ってはおかしいか
You'll catch my illness, Father.
病が父上に移ってしまいます
You think your illness can defeat me?
お前の病如きに俺が負けると？
N-No! But I know this is a busy time for you.
いえ でも 今はお忙しい時期だと
Uncle Yu-hon is so strong and strict.
ユホン伯父上 強くて厳しくて
He's nothing like Su-won.
スウォンとは全然違う
You must defeat this illness quickly.
病など 早急にぶち殺せ
I will!
はい
His intensity is amazing.
さすがな迫力
I think my fever's gone down already.
一気に熱下がった気がする
That was scary.
怖かった
Today's a happy day.
今日はなんて幸せな日なんでしょう
Okay! I will do my best to defeat my illness!
よし 頑張って病をぶち殺します
Go to sleep, idiot.
寝ろ アホ
Father...
父上
I feel so ill.
苦しいよ
Why won't you come see me?
どうして来てくれないの
Don't leave me alone.
一人にしないで
Princess, at least take one bite.
姫様 どうか一口でも
I don't want any.
欲しくない
Yona, you have to eat something.
ヨナ 少しは食べないと
益々不細工になるぜ
Or you'll get even uglier.
His Majesty hasn't come yet?
陛下はお見えになってないのか
No, I told him about the princess, but...
ええ 姫様の事はお伝えしたのですが
This is the king we're talking about.
あのお方の事だ
Perhaps he's too afraid of the illness to approach his own daughter.
病を恐れて我が娘にすら近づけないのでは
Quiet!
黙りなさい
He's the king, after all.
王は王だからな
Even at a time like this, he's hard at work.
こんな時にちゃんと仕事してんだから
I respect the old man.
俺はあのおっちゃんの事 見直してんぞ
Yeah!
I'm sorry.
ごめんね
一人だと思って ごめんね
I'm sorry for thinking I was alone.
That was a huge growl.
でっかいぐぅぅだな
おい いてぇ
Ow!
Yona, are you hungry?
ヨナ お腹すきました
I'll have something brought for you.
何か持って来させますね
Chicken porridge!
鶏粥
It's unbelievably disgusting!
びっくりするほど不味い
Really? It tastes bad, huh?
そうか 不味いか
Father!
父上
I made that.
それ 私が作ったんだよ
I thought I'd prepare your favorite food to make up for not coming to see you.
見舞いに来られなかったお詫びに
ヨナのお好物作ろうと思ってね
I made it according to the recipe.
料理日誌通りに作ったんだがなぁ
Oh? I thought it tasted bad.
あれ 不味いじゃないのかい
It tastes terrible!
すっごく不味い
Aw... We're all better.
あぁ 治っちゃった
You sound disappointed, Princess.
残念そうだな 姫さん
別に
Not really!
I'm disappointed.
私は残念です
Because you can't sleep next
to the princess anymore?
姫さんの隣で寝られないからか
I can sleep next to Yona anytime.
ヨナの隣は何時でも寝られますけど
But I wish the three of us could have slept together, with our colds, forever.
私はずっとずっとあのまま三人で風引いて寝てたかったです
Even if we aren't sick, that's easy enough.
別に風引いてなくても簡単だろ
We can stay together.
一緒に居る事くらい
You're right.
そうですね
Su-won, Hak, come again tomorrow.
スウォン ハク 明日も遊びに来てね
Always come play with me.
ずっとずっと 遊びに来てね
あれ
Huh?
There's no one here.
誰も居ない
Father!
父上
S-Su-won...
ス スウォン
ハク
Hak...
I'm sorry. I went to get water.
すみません 飲み水を汲みに行ったんで
The sky that the three of us
looked up at together is gone.
もう 三人で見上げた空は どこにもない
You should eat something.
少しでも食べた方がいいですよ
ここから先は 食糧が確保出来るか分からない
From here on, I don't know
if we'll be able to secure food.
She's growing weaker.
どんどん弱ってく
Not only her physical strength.
体力だけじゃない
Even after time has passed,
she still can't face reality.
時間が経っても 現実を直視出来なんだ
What are these?
なに これ
They're leeches.
蛭です
Hold still.
じっとして
They live in lakes and swamps,
and they suck your blood.
此奴は池や沼に住み 血を吸うんですよ
Blood...
血...
They won't kill you.
なに 大事には至らねぇ
I'll leave your clothes here.
服 ここに置いておきます
Once we gather our belongings, we'll leave.
荷物纏めたら出発します
この先ずっと姫さんはあのままだろか
Will the princess stay like this forever?
She doesn't eat. She only walks
if I pull her along by the hand.
食事もせず ただ俺に手を引かれて歩くだけ
She's like a doll.
まるで人形だ
Are you satisfied, Su-won?
満足か スウォン
You destroyed the days we spent together and the princess you treasured.
共に過ごした日々も
大事にしていた姫さんも 全て壊して
Does that satisfy you?
お前はそれで満足なのか
This is...
これは
She still had this.
またこんな物を持って
We'll rest here today.
今日はここで休みましょう
What's wrong? Did you lose something?
どうしました 何か落とし物でも
I don't need it.
要らない あんな物
I definitely don't need it.
絶対に要らない
But I love your hair, Yona.
私は好きですよ ヨナの髪
It's a beautiful red, like the sky at dawn.
暁の空の色です
Where are you going?
どこへ
I'm... I'm just...
ちょ ちょっと
I'll be right back.
すぐ戻るわ
The Su-won you know never existed.
貴方達の知ってるスウォンは
最初から居なかったんです
Should anyone get in my way,
I will cut him down.
道を阻むものがあれば 切り捨てます
Are you all right?
無事か
Why did you go this far?
Do you want to die?!
どうしてこんな所まで 死にたいのか
Damn it. Is this their nest?
クソ 巣窟かよ
ちっ ちょうどだ
B-Bring it on.
ハク
Hak...
Keep your mouth shut and hang on, Princess.
黙ってしがみついてな お姫さん
Think of me as a tool.
俺を道具と思えばいい
あんたが生きる為に 俺を使え
Use me so that you can live!
That's what I'm here for!
俺はその為にここに居る
Hak, I'm sorry-
ハク ごめん
Is this what you were looking for?
お探しの物はこれか
I can't forgive Su-won.
俺はスウォンを許さない
But more than that, I want you to live.
だがそれ以上に俺はあんたに生きて欲しい
Searching for that was the first thing you've done on your own since we entered these mountains.
あんたはこの山に入って初めて
自ら動いてそれを探しに行った
If it stops you from falling apart completely, I don't care what it is.
何でもいい 今はあんたを繋ぎとめられるのなら
Even if that means clinging to an illusion of the past.
例えそれが 未だ捨てきれない思いでも
I see. You haven't found them.
そうですか 二人は見つかりませんか
Should we send more troops after them?
追手を増やしますか
No, leave them be.
いや 放っておきましょう
You're allowing them to live?
生かしておくのですか
Now that they've left the castle, they're powerless.
城を出た彼らには何もできません
それより 我々には早急にやらねばならない事があります
Besides, there is something we must do immediately.
Do you see
wakaru kai
What I'm trying so hard to convey through my work?
muriyari demo sakuhin de tsutaetokitai koto wo
It's always been this way, hasn't it?
mukashi to kawaranai daro
The same obscure lyrics and background
yomizurai kashi mo haikei mo
I've always talked ideals
sasaeru da to ga erasou ni sa
Like supporting others
nando mo nando mo itta kedo
I hope you don't realize too early
kotoba no karusa omoishiru no wa
How irresponsible I was being with my words
hayasuginai you ni
There's a reason why the snow is so cold
yuki ga tsumetai wake nante
Since my hands are warmer than others'
boku no te ga hito yori atsui kara
When I hold your hand
kimi no sono te wo tsunaida toki
I'll be able to bring out the warmth in you
atatakai wo hikidasu tame
Next Time
The place we reached after escaping our pursuers
追手から逃れ 私達が辿り着いた場所
overflowed with warm smiles.
そこは暖かい笑顔に溢れていた
Next time, Akatsuki no Yona, episode 4:
次回 暁のヨナ 第四話
Episode 4:   The Wind Tribe
The Wind Tribe.
風の部族